# **ARJIT GUPTA**

arjitg@colostate.edu | linkedin.com/in/arjitg | arjitg.github.io | medium.com/@arjitg | Fort Collins, CO

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over 3+ years of experience in designing and building efficient software using various backend technologies, with experience with agile and working in big team projects. I am currently pursuing MCIS at Colorado State University and seeking internship opportunities in software development for summer 2023.

### **EDUCATION**

**COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY** [Masters in Computer Information Systems]

[Expected Dec 2023]

Fort Collins, CO | GPA: 4

<u>Courses:</u> Application Software Infrastructure, Business Application Development, Applied Data Mining, IT Project Management, Object Oriented Systems, Software Development Methodology, Business Intelligence

MNNIT ALLAHABAD [Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering]

[2015-2019]

Prayagraj, India | GPA: 3.5

<u>Courses:</u> Data Structures, Analysis of Algorithms, Database Management Systems, Automata Theory, Computer Networks, Graph Theory, Computer Organization, Operating Systems, Cryptography, Object Oriented Modelling, Distributed Systems, Pattern Recognition.

<u>Project:</u> Built a Chest X-Ray disease prediction system that predicted lung cancer probability from X-ray scans using machine learning tools from TensorFlow library in Python.

## **KEY SKILLS**

<u>Languages:</u> Python, C++, C#, MySQL, JavaScript, Jinja, HTML, CSS, Kubernetes, Microservices, Federation, MQTT <u>Tools:</u> Git, Postman, JIRA, Visual Studio, Knime, Zabbix, Kibana, Docker, AWS, .NET, Frappe, ERPNext, Metabase

### **EXPERIENCE**

[Graduate Assistant] COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY, [Fort Collins, CO]

[Jan 2023-Present]

Assist faculty with academic research and analytics.

[Senior Software Engineer] ELASTICRUN, [Pune, India]

[Jun 2019 - Sep 2022]

- Put-to-Light System [Python, MQTT, SQL, JavaScript]:
  - Designed and implemented an in-house PTL system using Modbus hardware which minimized human picking errors. Saved INR 0.5 million in costs.
- CFC Project [Python, SQL, JavaScript]:
  - Lead end-to-end software module design for online fulfillment centers with a team of 3. Increased revenue margins in the last-mile delivery operations by merging vehicle loads and cutting logistics costs by 10%.
- Brand EDI Project [Python, SQL, AWS, Metabase]:
  - Created a SQL based system using AWS to create pipelines for EDI with brands. Created dashboards and reports using Metabase used by key stakeholders.
- NFR [Python, SQL, ELK, RocksDB]:
  - Improved overall database performance by 30X using ELK. Published a research article on medium
  - Optimized locking scenarios on main transaction tables by tuning the traditional implementation of nested set tree structure used in frappe framework.
- Inventory Reconciliation System [Python, SQL, JavaScript]:
  - Designed a reconciliation module in ERPNext and reduced time spent in manual activity by 3+ hrs per day.
- Scorecard [Python, SQL, JavaScript, Microservices]:
  - Built a scoring application using APIs in a microservice architecture, which is used by over 10K+ users for ranking and internal incentives.
- IRN Project [Python, JavaScript, Jinja]:
  - Implemented an E-invoicing system which simplified manual taxation activity while processing over 50K+ invoices a day in real-time financial transactions.